Guide to the Sid Saltzman papers, 1950-2009.
Saltzman, Sid papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sid Saltzman papers, 1950-2009.
15-2-3808
Sidney. Saltzman
5 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Publications, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes papers documenting Sid Saltzman's work.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Emeritus professor in City and Regional Planning, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes correspondence, publications, research material on regional modeling, regional science, economic development and public policy analysis in the United States and abroad, and course material on quantitative and modeling, statistics, econometrics, input-output and social accounting matrix models, regional science and quantitative public policy analysis.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Saltzman, Sidney.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.College of Architecture, Art, and Planning.
Subjects:
Regional planning.; City planning.; Quantitative research.; Economic development.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- City and Regional Planning Department Meetings
  - CRP Department Meetings, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - CRP Department Meetings, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CRP Department Meetings, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - CRP Department Meetings, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Department Meetings and Commissions
  - Master of Regional Planning Theses, 1950-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alumni Survey Commission, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Orientation Information, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Undergraduate Urban & Regional Studies Material, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Technical Assistance Center, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Regional Science/Peace Science (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publicity/Awards (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Research - NYSEED Transparency (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Indonesia Project (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AAP Annual Report, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Washington Program (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Planning and Public Policy (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Conferences
  - Summer Industrial Engineering Workshop at Cornell-Notes, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Conferences, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Conferences/Workshop, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - ORSA/TIMS Joint National Meeting - Micro/Macro Causality in Socioeconomic Policy Models, April 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Conferences/Workshop, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - NCSA Workshop Part I, September 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - NCSA Workshop Part II, September 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Conferences/Workshop, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - National Center for Geographic Information and Analysis Conference -Notes, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Conference/GIS 1999 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Conferences/Workshop, 2000-2009 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Amsterdam Peace Science Conference, Europe Peace Science Conference, June 2002, June 2003 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - North East Regional Science Council Annual Meeting - Measuring Bi-National Economic Interdependence, November 2004 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Presentation: Exploring Alternative Strategies to Enhance Affordable Development Planning in a Decentralizing Environment, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Presentation at the Indonesian Regional Science Association - Exploring Multidimensional Affordable Planning for Regional Development, March 21, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Agendas, Abstracts, Etc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Correspondence
  - CRP Correspondence No Date (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 2000-2005 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence/Memos, 2005-2009 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence on "Chicago 10", A Joint Effort of Peacekeeping in the Middle East, September 2, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Testimony
  - Testimonies of W. Greene, T. Mount, S. Saltzman, September 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Research Grant Proposals
  - Research Proposals Not Dated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Research Proposal, 1960-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Research Proposal/Fellowships, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Grant Proposals & Supporting Documents, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Research Proposal on A Live System of Integrated Econometric Models for the Nation, New York State & New York City, January 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - NSF Research Grant, September 1973 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Proposed Fellowship Activities Program-Center for Environmental Studies in London, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Preliminary Proposal & Progress Report to National Science Foundation, June, December 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Research Proposal/Fellowships, 1975-1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Grant Proposals to National Science Foundation, April 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Grant Proposals Submitted to National Science Foundation and the Department of Commerce, April 1975, May 1976 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Proposal Submitted to the Applied Sciences & Research Applications Program, National Science Foundation, July 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Research Proposal: New York State Economic Forecasting, Part I, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Research Proposal: New York State Economic Forecasting, part II, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - A Proposal for A New York State Economic Forecasting Model and Revenue Estimating System, August 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Proposals Submitted to New York State Energy Research and Development Authority, August, December 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - A Proposal to the US Department of Energy for a Three-Year Institutional Grant for Energy Research, Feburary 1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Grant Proposal to Department of Energy, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Grant Proposal of 'Integrated Micro/Macro Policy Analysis', August 1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Grant Proposals/Supporting Documents 1980-1981, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Research Proposals/Fellowships, 1980-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Grant & Research Proposals, 1981-1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Research Proposals to National Science Foundation and University of Illinois, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Conference & Research Grant Proposals, April 1984, March 1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Grant Proposals and Supporting Documents, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Research Proposals/Fellowships, 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Research Proposals/Fellowships, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Grant Proposals, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Research Proposals/Fellowships, 2000-2005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Grant Proposals and Supporting Documents, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Course Material
  - Seminar Notes, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Course Documents-General, 1970s-2000s (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321/645 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Course Documents-CRP 321/646 1991-Summer 1992, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Course Documents-CRP 620 Planning Analysis (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Course Documents-CRP 730 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Course Documents-CRP 730 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Course Documents-CRP 730 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Course Documents-CRP 730 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Course Documents-CRP 730 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Course Documents-CRP 720 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Course Documents-CRP 789 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Course Documents-CRP 830 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Course Materials - CRP 731 and CRP 633 I, 1991-1998 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Course Materials - CRP 731 and CRP 633 II, 1991-1998 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Course Grades, Fall 1997, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Mathematica Policy Research Project
  - Mathematica Policy Research Project-Proposal Submitted to National Science Foudnation, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Mathematica Policy Research Project, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Mathematica Policy Research Project 1983, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Mathematica Policy Research Project, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mathematica Policy Research Project, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Kenya Project
  - Kenya Project Reports, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Draft Reports/Reference/Addendum by Prof. Saltzman (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, August 28, 1984-November 4, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, Not Dated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous, June 10 1983-June 21 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, Hand-Written (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Infrastructure Inventory And Underutilization Report (Unknown Author) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kenya Demographic Data by Areas (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Area Data on Service & Training Centers (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Area Data on Grain Storage Facilities/Livestock Holding Facilities (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Area Data on Infrastructure/Schools/Co-ops (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Area Data on Water Facilities/Health Facilities/Cattle Dip (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Personnel Related Documents
  - CV/Personnel Related, 1960s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - CV/Personnel Related, 1980-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - CV/Personnel Related, November, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Publications
  - Research Papers, Not Dated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Optimal Reorder Periods for Inventory System with Variable Costs of Ordering, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Publications on Industrial Engineering 1960-1966, 1960-1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - An Econometrics Model of a Firm, August 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Publications on Air Terminal Design in Israel 1966-1967, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Professional Education in Urban Planning: A Framework for Growth, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Planning for the Management of Economic Development in New York State, November 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Integrated Regional And National Econometric Models, April 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Publications on Integrated Regional/National Econometric Models, 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Publications on Regional Energy Demand Forecasting and Linked Macro/Micro Models, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Forecasting Regional Energy Demand: The Case of New York State (Technical Report), January 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Forecasting Regional Energy Demand: The Case of New York State (Technical Report), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Respond to NERA's Critique of the Cornell Group's Macro-Econometric Model of New York State, March 1979 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Publications on The Member Systems of The New York Power Pool, Feburary, April 1979 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Forecasting of the Demand for Major Fuels in New York State: 1980-1994 (Technical Report), September 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - A Regional Econometric Analysis of Energy Prices and Economic Activity, Circa 1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Forecasting Target Variables for the Department of the Treasury's Personal Individual Income Tax Simulation Model, November 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - A Study of the Energy-Economic-Demographic Interrelationships in the State of Maryland, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Demographic and Economic Aging of a 1975 PUS Based Math/CHRDS File to 1978, March 1981 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - A Guidebook for Analysis of State-Level Economic Impacts of an Energy Shortfall, June 1981 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Microsimulation and Regional Science, Nobember 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - A Regional Econometric Analysis of Energy Price and Economic Activity (Draft), Circa 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - For Designing, Documenting and Installing a Computer-Based Model of the Federal-State-Local Fiscal System in NY State, August 1982 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "Errata List for a Review and Evaluation of an Econometric Model of Puerto Rico"-Developed by the Governor's Economic and Financial Council, February 1983 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Socioeconomic Policy Analyses for New York State, November 1983 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Microprocessor Implementation of an Infrastructure Inventory Information System (IIIS), September 1984 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Project Description-Joint Project with Steve Caldwell, Dept. of Sociology and Sid Saltzman, Mid 1980s (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Draft of paper on estimating "Gross State Product", 1980s (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Rural Infrastructure Inventory Information System (RIIIS)-Continuation of the Design Process; and Addendum, February, April 1985 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - The Computer-Based National Budgeting System and District Focus (Draft and a First Report), August 1985 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Review of the Author's Prospectus & Selected Chapters of 'MVS JCL & Utilities'; Integrated Macro/Micro Models for Regional Planning, June 1985, January 1986 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Publications on Global Economic Models; On the Significance of Economic and Non-Economic Components of Regional Development, March, April, September 1989 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Contributions to the Cornell-NCSA Workshop on Large Scale Social Science Models, Spetember 1989 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Papers written by students and Saltzman, 1990s-2005 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Book Reviews on Publications on Global Models; Assessment/Evaluation Report of Microcomputer Training Program for UN. FAO, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Spatial Aspects of Global Econometric Models: A Framework and Proposal for Enhanced Regional Analysis, December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Publications on Regional Economic Impacts of Electric Power Development Projects, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Environmental Policy Analysis: An Environmental Computer General Equilibrium Approach for China, August 1995 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Analysis of Kodak's Role in Rochester Metropolitan Eocnomy Using a Social Accounting Matrix, October 1998 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Evaluating the Socio-Economic Impacts of the Erie Canal Corridor Initiative, March 1999 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Environmental Policy Analysis: An Environmental Computer General Equilibrium Approach for Developing Countries, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - "The Economic Impacts of Terrorism:An Alternative Method to Quantify the Effects on the New York City Economy of the 9/11 Attack on the World Trade Center"- joint papers with Tad Hara and Saltzman-presented at the 8th annual Graduate Conference, 2002? (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Publications on Bi-National Economic Interdependence: An Exploration of the Israel-Palestine Case, 2004-2005 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - "Regional and Spatial Econometric Analysis" by Matthew Drennan and Sidney Salzman (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Identifying the Direct and indirect Economic Effects of Electric Power Development Projects (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Computing Optimum Shrinkage Allowances for Small Order Sizes, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - An Exploratory Monthly Integrated Regional/National Economic Model, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - On the Stability and Updating of Interregional Social Accounting Matrices: An Empirical Study of Indonesian Models For 1985 and 1990 (Draft) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Analysis of Kodak's Role in the Rochester Metropolitan Economy Using a Social Accounting Matrix, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Road Transport and Economic Growth: An Explanatory Study of Indonesia (Draft), 1999 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Environmental Policy Analysis: An Environmental Computable General-Equilibrium Approach for Developing Countires, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Estimating the Economic Impacts of Terrorism: The Effects on the New York Economy of the 9/11 Attack on the World Trade Center, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Data and Others
  - Econometric Analysis of the Effects of a Fuel Shortfall n State Level Economic Activity, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Index of "Methods of Interregional and Regional Analysis" by Walter Isard, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript - Accuracy and Error Analysis (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Input-Output Modal Data of Washington State, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Data (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Data (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Organization of Basic Data for Input-Output Modals (Manuscript) (Box 4, Folder 13)